Sergey Kambalin

Senior Software Developer

kambalin@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/sergeykambalin

Professional software developer with 10+ years of experience in all stages of advanced web and mobile development. I continuously seek to keep abreast of technology trends and best programming practices and always willing to share my knowledge and experience with others.

Technical Skills

Languages TypeScript, JavaScript, PHP, GraphQL, MySQL

Frameworks React, React Native, Redux, Apollo GraphQL, GraphQL-PHP, Express **Tools** Webpack, Babel, Storybook, Lerna, NPM, Yarn, Composer, Docker

Tests Jest, Enzyme, React/DOM Testing Library

Professional Experience

Evolution Gaming

Senior Software Developer Nov 2019 - present

- · Migrated a complex legacy project from JavaScript/AngularJS to TypeScript/React with unit testing on Jest
- Refactored a legacy project from monolithic to modular structure
- · Developed an in-game chat module, heavily utilizing Websockets for realtime communication
- · Was involved in interviewing, mentoring, and onboarding activities

Technology stack:

- · TypeScript, JavaScript
- · React & Redux ecosystem
- Babel, Webpack, Storybook, Lerna + Yarn Workspaces, Jest, Enzyme, React/DOM Testing Library

IOLA

Senior Software Developer/Architect

Oct 2018 - Nov 2019

- Architected, developed, and successfully released React Native iOS and Android applications
- Developed PWA version of the application using React Native Web
- · Architected and developed a modular GraphQL server on PHP, supporting all major GraphQL features
- Implemented real-time GraphQL subscriptions on PHP using Server-Sent Events technology
- · Achieved a significant performance increase of the GraphQL server by reducing the number of DB queries using Data Loader pattern
- Refactored the GraphQL server following Relay specification
- · Developed micro-frontend UI Kit based on Web Components

Technology stack:

- React, React Native, React Native Web, GraphQL, Web Components
- · Babel, Webpack, Storybook, Lerna
- · SlimPHP, GraphQL-PHP

Klika Tech LLC

Senior Software Developer/Team Lead

Oct 2016 - Sep 2018

- Developed various company projects as a full-stack JavaScript/PHP developer
- · Led a team of 3 members developing JavaScript SDK, which is used across multiple projects
- Achieved 100% test coverage of the JavaScript SDK using Mocha, Chai, and Sinon
- · Was involved in interviewing, mentoring, and onboarding activities
- Was the leader of the company's frontend community of more than 50 members

Technology stack:

- React, Redux, Webpack, Babel, Mocha, Chai, Sinon
- · PHP, PHPUnit, NodeJs, Sails, Express

Skalfa Asia LLC

Senior Software Developer/Team Lead

Dec 2012 - Sep 2016

- Led architecting and development of a hybrid iOS/Android application based on Ionic Framework and SlimPHP
- Was a key developer in a team architecting and developing open source website platforms: Oxwall, Skadate
- · Led development of native iOS application on Objective C for the online dating platform: Skadate

Software Developer Jul 2010 - Dec 2012

Took part in the development of a high load SaaS solution: Wall.fm

Junior Software Developer Mar 2009 - Jul 2010

• Developed various PHP/JavaScript modules for online dating platform: Skadate

Education

International University of Kyrgyzstan

Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan